Guide to the 19th century newspaper illustrations collection, 1839-1894
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center
19th century newspaper illustrations collection
1839-1894
C0285
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
3.0 linear ft.
The collection consists of illustrations that appeared in Puck, Harper's Weekly, and Illustrated London News.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased in 2016.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of illustrations that appeared in Puck, Harper's Weekly, and Illustrated London News. The illustrations from Puck are largely satirical in nature and the subject matter is Gilded Age politics. The subject matter of the Harper's Weekly and Illustrated London News focus on the Civil War and Mount Vernon, the home of George Washington.
Arrangement
Organized by subject.
Related Material
Special Collections Research Center also holds the
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States--Politics and government.; Virginia--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Pictorial works.
Contents List
- 19th century newspaper illustrations collection, 1861-1894
  - Puck - "Who Laughs Last Laughs Best", 1894 (Box 1)
  - Puck - The Dawn of a Better Day, 1887 (Box 1)
  - Harper's Weekly - On the Road Between Washington and Alexandria, circa late 1800s (Box 1)
  - Harper's Weekly - Pictorial Map of the Seat of War, Showing..., 1861 (Box 1)
  - Harper's Weekly - Map of Part of Maryland and Virginia..., 1861 (Box 1)
  - The Illustrated London News - Civil War in America, 1862 (Box 1)
  - Washington's House, Mount Vernon, 1839 (Box 1)
  - Harper's Weekly - A Pilgrimage to Mount Vernon, 1886 (Box 1)
  - Puck - Reveille in the White House, 1885 (Box 1)
  - Harper's Weekly - The Room in Which George Washington Died, 1886 (Box 1)